avanset.com 2019-07-15

# Avanset | Leader in VCE Software | Privacy Policy

### Privacy Policy

Avanset (web-address is https://www.avanset.com) website including all the subsidiary pages (hereinafter referred to as the "Website", "we", "us", "our" and "ourselves") commits to strong and transparent privacy practices. Your privacy is really important to us, so whether you are new to the Website or a long-time user, please take the time to get to know our practices. Our Privacy Policy (hereinafter referred to as the "Privacy Policy") explains among other things what personal data we collect and why we collect it, how we use personal data, who we share personal data with, the choices we offer, including how to get access, change and/or remove personal data.

Please read this Privacy Policy carefully. By using or accessing the Website and its services, you acknowledge that you have read, understood, and agree to be bound to all the terms and conditions of this Privacy Policy. If you do not agree to this Privacy Policy and the applicable [Terms & Conditions](https://www.avanset.com/terms-and-conditions.html), please exit and do not access or use, this Website and any of its services.

While we have not made any material changes to the way we process data about our users, we have updated this policy to make it shorter and easier to read, and to comply with the EU General Data Protection Regulation coming into force on May 25, 2018. Feel free to [contact us](mailto:support@avanset.com) and ask any queries or questions that you may have pertaining to this Privacy Policy and its contents.

### I. What information do we get?

We collect some information from you directly, like information you enter yourself and data from third-party platforms you connect with the Website. We also collect some data automatically, like information about your device and what parts of our Website you interact with or spend time using.

#### I.I. Information you share with us

We may collect different information from or about you depending on how you use the Website.

If you create an account and use the Website, including through a third-party platform, we collect the information you provide directly. This information stored by us and associated with your account includes:

  * Account Data (hereinafter referred to as the "Account Data"): in order to use certain features, for example to get access to your purchases at the Website, you need to create a user account. When you create or update your account, we collect and store the data you provide, like your email address and password.
  * Profile Data: you can also choose to provide profile information like a gender, date of birth, photo, headline, website link, social media profiles or other data. Your Profile Data will be publicly viewable by others.
  * Shared Content: parts of the Website let you interact with other users or share content publicly, including by posting reviews, asking or answering questions and files you upload. Such shared content may be publicly viewable by others depending on where it is posted.
  * Account Payment Data: if you make purchases, we collect certain data about your purchase (such as your name and zip code) as necessary to process your order. You must provide certain payment and billing data directly to our payment processing partners, including your name, credit card information, billing address, and zip code. For security, the Website does not collect or store sensitive cardholder data, such as full credit card numbers or card authentication data.
  * Promotions and surveys: we may invite you to complete a survey or participate in a promotion (like promo-codes or challenge), either through the Website or a third-party platform. If you participate, we will collect and store the data you provide as part of participating, such as your name, email address or phone number. That data is subject to this Privacy Policy unless otherwise stated in the official rules of the promotion or in another privacy policy. The data collected will be used to administer the promotion or survey, including for notifying winners and distributing rewards. Where we use a third-party platform to administer a survey or promotion, the third party's privacy policy will apply.
  * Communications and Support: if you contact us for support or to report a problem or concern (regardless of whether you have created an account), we collect and store your contact information, messages and other data about you like your name, email address, location, operating system, IP address, and any other data you provide or that we collect through automated means (which we cover below). We use this data to respond to you and research your question or concern, in accordance with this Privacy Policy.

#### I.II. Information we collect through automated means

When you access the Website, we collect some information by automated means. This information is collected through the use of server log files and tracking technologies (as defined in the Paragraph II.I. of this Privacy Policy). It is stored by us and associated with your account. This information includes:

  * System Data (hereinafter referred to as the "System Data"): technical data about your computer or device, like your IP address, device type, operating system type and version, unique device identifiers, browser, browser language, domain and other systems data, and platform types.
  * Usage Data (hereinafter referred to as the "Usage Data"): usage statistics about your interactions with the Website, including pages accessed, time spent on pages or the Website, pages visited, features used, your search queries, click data, date and time, and other data regarding your use of the Website.
  * Approximate Geographic Data: an approximate geographic location, including information like country, city, and geographic coordinates, calculated based on your IP address.

### II. How do we get information about you?

We use tools like cookies, web beacons, analytics services and advertising providers to gather the data explained above. Some of these tools offer you the ability to opt out of data collection.

#### II.I. Cookies and data collection tools

#### II.I.I. What are cookies?

Cookies are small text files stored by your browser as you browse the internet. They can be used to collect, store, and share data about your activities across websites, including on the Website. Cookies also allow us to remember things about your visits to the Website, like your preferred language, and to make the site easier to use.

We use both session cookies, which expire after a short time or when you close your browser, and persistent cookies, which remain stored in your browser for a set period of time. We use session cookies to identify you during a single browsing session, like when you log into the Website. We use persistent cookies where we need to identify you over a longer period, like when you request that we keep you signed in.

#### II.I.II. Why does the Website use cookies and similar technologies?

We use cookies and similar technologies like web beacons, pixel tags, or local shared objects ("flash cookies"), to deliver, measure and improve our services in various ways. We use these cookies both when you visit our site and services through a browser and through our mobile version. As we adopt additional technologies, we may also gather additional data through other methods.

We use cookies for the following purposes:

  * Authentication and security: to log you into the Website; to protect your security; to help detect and fight spam, abuse, and other activities that violate the Website's agreements.
  * Preferences: to remember data about your browser and your preferences; to remember your settings and other choices you've made.
  * Analytics and research: to help us improve and understand how people use the Website. We also work with a number of analytics partners, including Google Analytics, who use cookies and similar technologies to help us analyze how users use the Website, including by noting the sites from which you arrive. Those service providers may either collect that data themselves or we may disclose it to them. You can opt out of some of these services through tools like the Google Analytics Opt-out Browser Add-on.
  * Personalized content: to customize the Website with more relevant content.
  * Advertising: to provide you with more relevant advertising.

Please note that where advertising technology is integrated into the Website, you may still receive advertising on other websites and applications, but it will not be tailored to your interests.

When using mobile applications you may also receive tailored in-app advertisements. Apple iOS, Android OS and Microsoft Windows each provide its own rules on how to control in-app tailored advertising. For other devices and operating systems, you should review your privacy settings or contact your platform operator.

#### II.I.III. What are cookies privacy options?

You have a number of options to control or limit how we and our partners use cookies:

  * Most browsers automatically accept cookies, but you can change your browser settings to decline cookies by consulting your browser's support articles. If you decide to decline cookies, please note that you may not be able to sign in, customize, or use some interactive features in the Website.
  * Flash cookies operate differently than browser cookies, so your browser's cookie-management tools may not remove them. To learn more about how to manage Flash cookies, see Adobe's [ article on managing flash cookies](https://helpx.adobe.com/flash-player/kb/disable-local-shared-objects-flash.html) and [ Website Storage Settings panel](http://www.macromedia.com/support/documentation/en/flashplayer/help/settings_manager07.html).
  * To get information and control cookies used for tailored advertising from participating companies, see the consumer opt-out pages for the [Network Advertising Initiative](http://www.networkadvertising.org/choices) and [Digital Advertising Alliance](http://www.aboutads.info/choices/), or if you're located in the European Union, visit the [Your Online Choices site](http://www.youronlinechoices.eu/). To opt out of Google Analytics' display advertising or customize Google Display Network ads, visit the [Google Ads Settings page](https://www.google.com/settings/ads).

#### II.II. How do we use cookies and data collection tools?

The Website and service providers acting on our behalf (like Google Analytics and third party advertisers) use server log files and automated data collection tools like cookies, tags, scripts, customized links, device or browser fingerprints, and web beacons (together, "Data Collection Tools") when you access and use the Website. These Data Collection Tools automatically track and collect certain System Data and Usage Data (as defined in the Paragraph I of this Privacy Policy) when you use the Website. In some cases, we tie data gathered through those Data Collection Tools to other data that we collect as described in this Privacy Policy.

We use cookies for things like analyzing your use of the Website, personalizing your experience, making it easier to log into the Website, and recognizing you when you return. We use web beacons (small objects that allow us to measure the actions of visitors and users using the Website) for things like identifying whether a page was visited, identifying whether an email was opened, and advertising more efficiently by excluding current users from certain promotional messages or identifying the source of a new mobile app download.

The Website uses the following types of cookies:

  * Preferences: cookies that remember data about your browser and preferred settings that affect the appearance and behavior of the Website (like your preferred language).
  * Security: cookies used to enable you to log in and access the Website; protect against fraudulent logins; and help detect and prevent abuse or unauthorized use of your account.
  * Functional: cookies that store functional settings (like the volume level you set for video playback).
  * Session State: cookies that track your interactions with the Website to help us improve the Website and your browsing experience, remember your login details, and enable processing of your purchases at the Website. These are strictly necessary for the Website to work properly, so if you disable them then certain functionalities will break or be unavailable.

You can set your web browser to alert you about attempts to place cookies on your computer, limit the types of cookies you allow, or refuse cookies altogether. If you do, you may not be able to use some or all features of the Website, and your experience may be different or less functional.

Some of the third-party partners who provide certain features on our site may also use Local Storage Objects (also known as flash cookies or LSOs) to collect and store data.

#### II.III. Analytics

We use third-party browser and mobile analytics services like Google Analytics on the Website. These services use Data Collection Tools to help us analyze your use of the Website, including information like the third-party website you arrive from, how often you visit, events within the Website, usage and performance data, and where the application was downloaded from. We use this data to improve the Website, better understand how the Website perform on different devices, and provide information that may be of interest to you. 

#### II.IV. Online advertising

We ca use third-party advertising services like Taboola, Facebook, Google's ad services and other ad networks and ad servers to deliver advertising about our Website on other websites and applications you use. The ads may be based on things we know about you, like your Usage Data and System Data (as defined in the Paragraph I of this Privacy Policy), and things that these ad service providers know about you based on their tracking data. The ads can be based on your recent activity or activity over time and across other sites and services, and may be tailored to your interests.

Depending on the types of advertising services we use, they may place cookies or other tracking technologies on your computer, smartphone, tablet or other device to collect data about your use of our Website, and may access those tracking technologies in order to serve these tailored advertisements to you. To help deliver tailored advertising, we may provide these service providers with a hashed, anonymized version of your email address (in a non-human-readable form) and content that you share publicly on the Website.

When using mobile applications you may also receive tailored in-app advertisements. Apple iOS, Android OS and Microsoft Windows each provide their own rules on how to control in-app tailored advertising. For other devices and operating systems, you should review your privacy settings or contact your platform operator.

### III. What do we use information from you for?

We use your data to do things like provide our Website, communicate with you, troubleshoot issues, secure against fraud and abuse, improve and update our Website, analyze how people use our Website, serve personalized advertising, and as required by law or necessary for safety and integrity.

We use the data we collect through your use of the Website to:

  * Provide and administer the Website, including to display customized content and facilitate communication with other users;
  * Process your requests and orders for products, specific services, information or other features;
  * Communicate with you about your account by: 
    * Responding to your questions and concerns;
    * Sending you administrative messages and information, notifications about changes to our Website, and updates to our agreements;
    * Sending you information and in-app messages about new products, newservices, new features, promotions, newsletters;
    * Sending push notifications to your wireless device to provide updates and other relevant messages (which you can manage from the "options" or "settings" page of the mobile app);
  * Manage your account preferences;
  * Facilitate the Website' technical functioning, including troubleshooting and resolving issues, securing the Website, and preventing fraud and abuse;
  * Solicit feedback from users;
  * Market and administer surveys and promotions administered or sponsored by the Website;
  * Learn more about you by linking your data with additional data through third-party data providers or analyzing the data with the help of analytics service providers;
  * Identify unique users across devices;
  * Tailor advertisements across devices;
  * Improve our Website and develop new products, services, and features;
  * Analyze trends and traffic, track purchases, and track usage data;
  * Advertise the Website on third-party websites and applications;
  * As required or permitted by law; or
  * As we, in our sole discretion, otherwise determine to be necessary to ensure the safety or integrity of our users, employees, third parties, the public or our Website.

### IV. Who do we share information with?

We share certain data about you with some companies performing services for us, analytics and data enrichment providers, your social media providers, companies helping us run promotions and surveys and advertising companies who help us promote our Website. We may also share your data as needed for security, legal compliance or as part of a corporate restructuring. Lastly, we can share data in other ways if it is aggregated or de-identified or if we get your consent.

We may share your data with third parties under the following circumstances or as otherwise described in this Privacy Policy:

  * With Service Providers, Contractors and Agents: we share your data with third-party companies who perform services on our behalf, like payment processing, data analysis, marketing and advertising services (including retargeted advertising), email and hosting services, and customer services and support. These service providers may access your personal data and are required to use it solely as we direct, to provide our requested service.
  * With Analytics and Data Enrichment Services: as part of our use of third-party analytics tools like Google Analytics, we share certain contact information, Account Data, System Data, Usage Data (as defined in the Paragraph I of this Privacy Policy), or de-identified data as needed. De-identified data means data where we've removed things like your name and email address and replaced it with a token ID. This allows these providers to provide analytics services or match your data with publicly-available database information (including contact and social information from other sources). We do this to communicate with you in a more effective and customized manner.
  * To Power Social Media Features: The social media features in the Website (like the Facebook Like button) may allow the third-party social media provider to collect things like your IP address and which page of the Website you're visiting, and to set a cookie to enable the feature. Your interactions with these features are governed by the third-party company's privacy policy.
  * To Administer Promotions and Surveys: we may share your data as necessary to administer, market or sponsor promotions and surveys you choose to participate in, as required by applicable law (like to provide a winners list or make required filings), or in accordance with the rules of the promotion or survey.
  * For Advertising: if we decide to offer advertising in the future, we may use and share certain System Data and Usage Data with third-party advertisers and networks to show general demographic and preference information among our users. We may also allow advertisers to collect System Data through Data Collection Tools (as detailed in the Paragraph II.I. of this Privacy Policy), and to use this data to offer you targeted ad delivery to personalize your user experience (through behavioral advertising) and undertake web analytics. Advertisers may also share with us the data they collect about you. To learn more or opt out from participating ad networks' behavioral advertising, please check the Paragraph VI.I. of this Privacy Policy below. Note that if you opt out, you'll continue to be served generic ads.
  * For Security and Legal Compliance: we may disclose your data to third parties if we (in our sole discretion) have a good faith belief that the disclosure is: 
    * Permitted or required by law;
    * Requested as part of a judicial, governmental, or legal inquiry, order, or proceeding;
    * Reasonably necessary as part of a valid subpoena, warrant, or other legally-valid request;
    * Reasonably necessary to enforce our Terms of Use, Privacy Policy, and other legal agreements;
    * Required to detect, prevent, or address fraud, abuse, misuse, potential violations of law (or rule or regulation), or security or technical issues; or
    * Reasonably necessary in our discretion to protect against imminent harm to the rights, property, or safety of the Website, our users, employees, members of the public, or our Website;
    * We may also disclose data about you to our auditors and legal advisors in order to assess our disclosure obligations and rights under this Privacy Policy.
  * During a Change in Control: if the Website undergoes a business transaction like a merger, acquisition, corporate divestiture, or dissolution (including bankruptcy), or a sale of all or some of its assets, we may share, disclose, or transfer all of your data to the successor organization during such transition or in contemplation of a transition (including during due diligence).
  * After Aggregation/De-identification: we can disclose or use aggregate or de-identified data for any purpose.
  * With Your Permission: with your consent, we may share data to third parties outside the scope of this Privacy Policy.

### V. Security

We use appropriate security based on the type and sensitivity of data being stored. As with any internet-enabled system, there is always a risk of unauthorized access, so it's important to protect your password and to contact us if you suspect any unauthorized access to your account.

The Website takes appropriate security measures to protect against unauthorized access, alteration, disclosure, or destruction of your personal data that we collect and store. These measures vary based on the type and sensitivity of the data. Unfortunately, however, no system can be 100% secured, so we cannot guarantee that communications between you and the Website, the Website, or any information provided to us in connection with the data we collect through the Website will be free from unauthorized access by third parties. Your password is an important part of our security system, and it is your responsibility to protect it. You should not share your password with any third party, and if you believe your password or account has been compromised, you should change it immediately and [contact us](mailto:support@avanset.com) with any concerns.

### VI. Users' rights

You have certain rights around the use of your data, including the ability to opt out of promotional emails, cookies, and collection of your data by certain analytics providers. You can update or terminate your account from within our Website, and can also contact us for individual rights requests about your personal data. Parents who believe we've unintentionally collected personal data about their underage child should contact us for help deleting that information.

#### VI.I. Users' choices about the use of their information

You can choose not to provide certain data to us, but you may not be able to use certain features of the Website.

  * To stop receiving promotional communications from us, you can opt out by using the unsubscribe mechanism in the promotional communication you receive or by changing the email preferences in your account. Note that regardless of your email preference settings, we will send you transactional and relationship messages regarding the Website, including administrative confirmations, order confirmations, important updates about the Website, and notices about our policies.
  * The browser or device you use may allow you to control cookies and other types of local data storage. Your wireless device may also allow you to control whether location or other data is collected and shared.
  * To opt out of Google's display advertising or customize Google Display Network ads, visit the [Google Ads Settings page](https://www.google.com/settings/ads).
  * To opt out of allowing Google Analytics, please check [ Google Analytics Opt-out Browser Add-on](https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout).

#### VI.II. Accessing, updating, and deleting of your personal information

You can access and update your personal data that the Website collects and maintains as follows: 

  * To update data you provide directly, log into your account and update your account at any time.
  * To terminate your account: 
    * Please visit your [profile settings page](https://www.avanset.com/login.html) and follow the steps detailed there.
    * If you have any issues terminating your account [contact us](mailto:support@avanset.com).
    * Please note: even after your account is terminated, some or all of your data may still be visible to others, including without limitation any data that has been (a) copied, stored or disseminated by other users (like comments); (b) shared or disseminated by you or others (including in your shared content); or (c) posted to a third-party platform. Even after your account is terminated, we retain your data for as long as we have a legitimate purpose to do so (and in accordance with applicable law), including to assist with legal obligations, resolve disputes, and enforce our agreements. We may retain and disclose such data pursuant to this Privacy Policy after your account has been terminated.
  * To request to access, correct, or delete your personal data, [contact us](mailto:support@avanset.com) directly. Please allow up to 30 days for a response. For your protection, we may require that the request be sent through the email address associated with your account, and we may need to verify your identity before implementing your request. Please note that we retain certain data where we have a lawful basis to do so, including for mandatory record-keeping and to complete transactions.

#### VI.III. Our Privacy Policy regarding to children

We recognize the privacy interests of children and encourage parents and guardians to take an active role in their children's online activities and interests. Children under 13 (or under 16 in the European Economic Area) should not use the Website. If we learn that we've collected personal data from a child under those ages, we will take reasonable steps to delete it.

Parents who believe that the Website may have collected personal data from a child under those ages can [contact us](mailto:support@avanset.com) that it be removed.

### VII. Specified jurisdiction rules

#### VII.I. Users in California

If you are a California resident, you have the right to request certain details about what personal information we share with third parties for those third parties' direct marketing purposes. To submit your request, [contact us](mailto:support@avanset.com) with the phrase "California Shine the Light" and include your mailing address, state of residence, and email address.

Since the internet industry is still working on Do Not Track standards, solutions, and implementations, we do not currently recognize or respond to browser-initiated Do Not Track signals.

#### VII.II. Users outside of the USA

In operating the Website, we process data as a controller (as such terms are defined in EU General Data Protection Regulation). As a controller, the Website is committed to fulfill data subjects' ("Users") GDPR rights.

### VIII. Updates & contact info

#### VIII.I. Modifications to this Privacy Policy

From time to time, we may update this Privacy Policy. If we make any material change to it, we will notify you via email, through a notification posted on the Website, or as required by applicable law. We will also include a summary of the key changes. Unless stated otherwise, modifications will become effective on the day they are posted.

As permitted by applicable law, if you continue to use the Website after the effective date of any change, then your access and/or use will be deemed an acceptance of (and agreement to follow and be bound by) the revised Privacy Policy. The revised Privacy Policy supersedes all previous Privacy Policies.

#### VIII.II. Interpretation

Any capitalized terms not defined in this policy are defined as specified in our [Terms & Conditions](https://www.avanset.com/terms-and-conditions.html).

#### VIII.III. Questions

If you have any questions, concerns, or disputes regarding our Privacy Policy, please feel free to contact our Data Protection Officer via email [support@avanset.com](mailto:support@avanset.com) or via postal mail to Tradesol Group Ltd: 71-75 Shelton Street, London, Greater London, United Kingdom, WC2H 9JQ.

Last updated: May 22, 2018
